Guide to the Chester Wells Purington Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Chester Wells Purington papers
1898-1925
MS 595
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
Correspondence, drafts of various books and articles concerning Purington's travels in Russia and Siberia as a mining engineer ca. 1898-1900, and other papers.
Purington, Chester Wells, 1871-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. William Zuill in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
These papers consist largely of unpublished manuscripts of books and articles describing the travels of Chester W. Purington (1871-\) in Siberia and to a lesser extent in western Alaska before World War I, and his work there as a mining engineer. Purington discusses not only his mining and prospecting, but also many aspects of Siberia and Russia and their inhabitants in the late 1890s and early 1900s.
Other material in the papers includes a few letters dealing with the publication of Purington's writings, a letter describing the wreck of the Carioca, passports and other documents, memorabilia, and printed matter on the subjects of Siberia and mining. The papers were given to Yale University by Mr. and Mrs. William Zuill in 1969.
Mines and mineral resources; Europe; Siberia (Russia) -- Description and travel; Soviet Union -- Description and travel; Mining engineers; Purington, Chester Wells, 1871-
- Inventory
  - Correspondence, 1917-1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Writings:
    - "Free Siberia" (draft), [1917?] (Box 1, Folder 2 - 4)
    - "From a Western Perspective", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Siberia of Today" (draft), undated (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
    - Printed articles on Siberia, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Short writings on mining in Siberia, 1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Short writings on Siberia, Alaska, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Passports and other documents, 1898-1917 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memorabilia, 1914-1921, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Printed matter, 1916-1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)